<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OpenClaw</title>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.9</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:23:25 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9194</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.9</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.9</h2>
<h3>Added</h3>
<ul>
<li>iOS: alpha node app + setup-code onboarding. (#11756) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Channels: comprehensive BlueBubbles and channel cleanup. (#11093) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Plugins: device pairing + phone control plugins (Telegram <code>/pair</code>, iOS/Android node controls). (#11755) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Tools: add Grok (xAI) as a <code>web_search</code> provider. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Gateway: add agent management RPC methods for the web UI (<code>agents.create</code>, <code>agents.update</code>, <code>agents.delete</code>). (#11045) Thanks @advaitpaliwal.</li>
<li>Web UI: show a Compaction divider in chat history. (#11341) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: include runtime shell in agent envelopes. (#1835) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Paths: add <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code> for overriding the home directory used by internal path resolution. (#12091) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: harden quote parsing; preserve quote context; avoid QUOTE_TEXT_INVALID; avoid nested reply quote misclassification. (#12156) Thanks @rybnikov.</li>
<li>Telegram: recover proactive sends when stale topic thread IDs are used by retrying without <code>message_thread_id</code>. (#11620)</li>
<li>Telegram: render markdown spoilers with <code><tg-spoiler></code> HTML tags. (#11543) Thanks @ezhikkk.</li>
<li>Telegram: truncate command registration to 100 entries to avoid <code>BOT_COMMANDS_TOO_MUCH</code> failures on startup. (#12356) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Telegram: match DM <code>allowFrom</code> against sender user id (fallback to chat id) and clarify pairing logs. (#12779) Thanks @liuxiaopai-ai.</li>
<li>Onboarding: QuickStart now auto-installs shell completion (prompt only in Manual).</li>
<li>Auth: strip embedded line breaks from pasted API keys and tokens before storing/resolving credentials.</li>
<li>Web UI: make chat refresh smoothly scroll to the latest messages and suppress new-messages badge flash during manual refresh.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: include provider-specific settings in the web search cache key, and pass <code>inlineCitations</code> for Grok. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: normalize direct Perplexity model IDs while keeping OpenRouter model IDs unchanged. (#12795) Thanks @cdorsey.</li>
<li>Model failover: treat HTTP 400 errors as failover-eligible, enabling automatic model fallback. (#1879) Thanks @orenyomtov.</li>
<li>Errors: prevent false positive context overflow detection when conversation mentions "context overflow" topic. (#2078) Thanks @sbking.</li>
<li>Gateway: no more post-compaction amnesia; injected transcript writes now preserve Pi session <code>parentId</code> chain so agents can remember again. (#12283) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Gateway: fix multi-agent sessions.usage discovery. (#11523) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: recover from context overflow caused by oversized tool results (pre-emptive capping + fallback truncation). (#11579) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Subagents/compaction: stabilize announce timing and preserve compaction metrics across retries. (#11664) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron: share isolated announce flow and harden scheduling/delivery reliability. (#11641) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron tool: recover flat params when LLM omits the <code>job</code> wrapper for add requests. (#12124) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Gateway/CLI: when <code>gateway.bind=lan</code>, use a LAN IP for probe URLs and Control UI links. (#11448) Thanks @AnonO6.</li>
<li>Hooks: fix bundled hooks broken since 2026.2.2 (tsdown migration). (#9295) Thanks @patrickshao.</li>
<li>Routing: refresh bindings per message by loading config at route resolution so binding changes apply without restart. (#11372) Thanks @juanpablodlc.</li>
<li>Exec approvals: render forwarded commands in monospace for safer approval scanning. (#11937) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
<li>Config: clamp <code>maxTokens</code> to <code>contextWindow</code> to prevent invalid model configs. (#5516) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Thinking: allow xhigh for <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2-codex</code> and <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2</code>. (#11646) Thanks @LatencyTDH.</li>
<li>Discord: support forum/media thread-create starter messages, wire <code>message thread create --message</code>, and harden routing. (#10062) Thanks @jarvis89757.</li>
<li>Paths: structurally resolve <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code>-derived home paths and fix Windows drive-letter handling in tool meta shortening. (#12125) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Memory: set Voyage embeddings <code>input_type</code> for improved retrieval. (#10818) Thanks @mcinteerj.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: reuse default model cache across agents instead of re-downloading per agent. (#12114) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Media understanding: recognize <code>.caf</code> audio attachments for transcription. (#10982) Thanks @succ985.</li>
<li>State dir: honor <code>OPENCLAW_STATE_DIR</code> for default device identity and canvas storage paths. (#4824) Thanks @kossoy.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.9/OpenClaw-2026.2.9.zip" length="22872529" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="zvgwqlgqI7J5Gsi9VSULIQTMKqLiGE5ulC6NnRLKtOPphQsHZVdYSWm0E90+Yq8mG4lpsvbxQOSSPxpl43QTAw=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.3</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:47:10 -0800</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>8900</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.3</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.3</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: remove last <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot-handlers.ts</code>, use Grammy types directly, deduplicate <code>StickerMetadata</code>. Zero <code>@ts-nocheck</code> remaining in <code>src/telegram/</code>. (#9206)</li>
<li>Telegram: remove <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot-message.ts</code>, type deps via <code>Omit<BuildTelegramMessageContextParams></code>, widen <code>allMedia</code> to <code>TelegramMediaRef[]</code>. (#9180)</li>
<li>Telegram: remove <code>@ts-nocheck</code> from <code>bot.ts</code>, fix duplicate <code>bot.catch</code> error handler (Grammy overrides), remove dead reaction <code>message_thread_id</code> routing, harden sticker cache guard. (#9077)</li>
<li>Onboarding: add Cloudflare AI Gateway provider setup and docs. (#7914) Thanks @roerohan.</li>
<li>Onboarding: add Moonshot (.cn) auth choice and keep the China base URL when preserving defaults. (#7180) Thanks @waynelwz.</li>
<li>Docs: clarify tmux send-keys for TUI by splitting text and Enter. (#7737) Thanks @Wangnov.</li>
<li>Docs: mirror the landing page revamp for zh-CN (features, quickstart, docs directory, network model, credits). (#8994) Thanks @joshp123.</li>
<li>Messages: add per-channel and per-account responsePrefix overrides across channels. (#9001) Thanks @mudrii.</li>
<li>Cron: add announce delivery mode for isolated jobs (CLI + Control UI) and delivery mode config.</li>
<li>Cron: default isolated jobs to announce delivery; accept ISO 8601 <code>schedule.at</code> in tool inputs.</li>
<li>Cron: hard-migrate isolated jobs to announce/none delivery; drop legacy post-to-main/payload delivery fields and <code>atMs</code> inputs.</li>
<li>Cron: delete one-shot jobs after success by default; add <code>--keep-after-run</code> for CLI.</li>
<li>Cron: suppress messaging tools during announce delivery so summaries post consistently.</li>
<li>Cron: avoid duplicate deliveries when isolated runs send messages directly.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Heartbeat: allow explicit accountId routing for multi-account channels. (#8702) Thanks @lsh411.</li>
<li>TUI/Gateway: handle non-streaming finals, refresh history for non-local chat runs, and avoid event gap warnings for targeted tool streams. (#8432) Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Shell completion: auto-detect and migrate slow dynamic patterns to cached files for faster terminal startup; add completion health checks to doctor/update/onboard.</li>
<li>Telegram: honor session model overrides in inline model selection. (#8193) Thanks @gildo.</li>
<li>Web UI: fix agent model selection saves for default/non-default agents and wrap long workspace paths. Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Web UI: resolve header logo path when <code>gateway.controlUi.basePath</code> is set. (#7178) Thanks @Yeom-JinHo.</li>
<li>Web UI: apply button styling to the new-messages indicator.</li>
<li>Security: keep untrusted channel metadata out of system prompts (Slack/Discord). Thanks @KonstantinMirin.</li>
<li>Security: enforce sandboxed media paths for message tool attachments. (#9182) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Security: require explicit credentials for gateway URL overrides to prevent credential leakage. (#8113) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Security: gate <code>whatsapp_login</code> tool to owner senders and default-deny non-owner contexts. (#8768) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Voice call: harden webhook verification with host allowlists/proxy trust and keep ngrok loopback bypass.</li>
<li>Voice call: add regression coverage for anonymous inbound caller IDs with allowlist policy. (#8104) Thanks @victormier.</li>
<li>Cron: accept epoch timestamps and 0ms durations in CLI <code>--at</code> parsing.</li>
<li>Cron: reload store data when the store file is recreated or mtime changes.</li>
<li>Cron: deliver announce runs directly, honor delivery mode, and respect wakeMode for summaries. (#8540) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Telegram: include forward_from_chat metadata in forwarded messages and harden cron delivery target checks. (#8392) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>macOS: fix cron payload summary rendering and ISO 8601 formatter concurrency safety.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.3/OpenClaw-2026.2.3.zip" length="22530161" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="7eHUaQC6cx87HWbcaPh9T437+LqfE9VtQBf4p9JBjIyBrqGYxxp9KPvI5unEjg55j9j2djCXhseSMeyyRmvYBg=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.2</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:04:17 -0800</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>8809</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.2</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.2</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Feishu: add Feishu/Lark plugin support + docs. (#7313) Thanks @jiulingyun (openclaw-cn).</li>
<li>Web UI: add Agents dashboard for managing agent files, tools, skills, models, channels, and cron jobs.</li>
<li>Memory: implement the opt-in QMD backend for workspace memory. (#3160) Thanks @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Security: add healthcheck skill and bootstrap audit guidance. (#7641) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Config: allow setting a default subagent thinking level via <code>agents.defaults.subagents.thinking</code> (and per-agent <code>agents.list[].subagents.thinking</code>). (#7372) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Docs: zh-CN translations seed + polish, pipeline guidance, nav/landing updates, and typo fixes. (#8202, #6995, #6619, #7242, #7303, #7415) Thanks @AaronWander, @taiyi747, @Explorer1092, @rendaoyuan, @joshp123, @lailoo.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Security: require operator.approvals for gateway /approve commands. (#1) Thanks @mitsuhiko, @yueyueL.</li>
<li>Security: Matrix allowlists now require full MXIDs; ambiguous name resolution no longer grants access. Thanks @MegaManSec.</li>
<li>Security: enforce access-group gating for Slack slash commands when channel type lookup fails.</li>
<li>Security: require validated shared-secret auth before skipping device identity on gateway connect.</li>
<li>Security: guard skill installer downloads with SSRF checks (block private/localhost URLs).</li>
<li>Security: harden Windows exec allowlist; block cmd.exe bypass via single &. Thanks @simecek.</li>
<li>fix(voice-call): harden inbound allowlist; reject anonymous callers; require Telnyx publicKey for allowlist; token-gate Twilio media streams; cap webhook body size (thanks @simecek)</li>
<li>Media understanding: apply SSRF guardrails to provider fetches; allow private baseUrl overrides explicitly.</li>
<li>fix(webchat): respect user scroll position during streaming and refresh (#7226) (thanks @marcomarandiz)</li>
<li>Telegram: recover from grammY long-poll timed out errors. (#7466) Thanks @macmimi23.</li>
<li>Agents: repair malformed tool calls and session transcripts. (#7473) Thanks @justinhuangcode.</li>
<li>fix(agents): validate AbortSignal instances before calling AbortSignal.any() (#7277) (thanks @Elarwei001)</li>
<li>Media understanding: skip binary media from file text extraction. (#7475) Thanks @AlexZhangji.</li>
<li>Onboarding: keep TUI flow exclusive (skip completion prompt + background Web UI seed); completion prompt now handled by install/update.</li>
<li>TUI: block onboarding output while TUI is active and restore terminal state on exit.</li>
<li>CLI/Zsh completion: cache scripts in state dir and escape option descriptions to avoid invalid option errors.</li>
<li>fix(ui): resolve Control UI asset path correctly.</li>
<li>fix(ui): refresh agent files after external edits.</li>
<li>Docs: finish renaming the QMD memory docs to reference the OpenClaw state dir.</li>
<li>Tests: stub SSRF DNS pinning in web auto-reply + Gemini video coverage. (#6619) Thanks @joshp123.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.2/OpenClaw-2026.2.2.zip" length="22519052" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="a6viD+aS5EfY/RkPIPMfoQQNkJCk6QTdV5WobXFxyYwURskUm8/nXTHVXsCh1c5+0WKUnmlDIyf0i+6IWiavAA=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>